我們開始一個新的系列
是Jesus is Lord
Chinese New Year我們學了什麼?
The Lord is the true blessing
是不是?
不是收到利是
不是收到吃飯等等
就有Blessing
The true blessing comes from the Lord
是不是?
True blessing comes from the Lord
Only through Him do we have eternal life
第二
上個禮拜我們學了什麼?
The Lord over the Sabbath
The Lord of the Sabbath
是不是?
God is the Lord
Jesus is the Lord over the Sabbath
今天我們會學
The Lord over nature
Jesus is Lord over nature
我們會讀
Chapter 8
Let's read Chapter 8 together
我們讀中文一起
看不看到中文?
看不到
OK 讀英文吧
我們一起讀英文
OK Ready
1, 2, 3
Jesus said to the disciples
Let's go over to the other side
So they got into the boat and set out
As they sailed, he fell asleep
A squall came down
So that the boat was being swamped
And they were in great danger
The disciples went and woke him
Saying, "Master! Master!
We're going to drown!"
He got up and rebuked the wind
And raging waters
The storm subsided
And all was calm
"Where is your faith?"
He asked his disciples
In fear and in amazement
Asked one another
"Who is this?"
He commands even the winds
And the waters
And they obey him
我們今天會看四個S
不是我們的任務
那四個S是
今天的sermon
The storm
The scream
The scrutiny
And the solution
OK
四個S
首先我們看
The storm
誰叫他們去湖裡的?
Who told them to go into the lake?
誰叫他們進去湖裡的?
記不記得?
是耶穌,是不是?
耶穌說什麼?
Let's go to the other side of the lake
那些門徒怎麼樣?
他就說
不知道,我們先看看預測
怎麼樣,是不是?
我們看看會不會下雪
下雨
打風
我們先看看天氣好不好
是不是?
Is it nice beach weather?
那邊是不是好的海灘天氣,是不是?
沒有,他們沒有質疑耶穌
他就這樣怎麼樣?
They went straight away
They took steps to follow Jesus
那他們跟隨耶穌的時候
Let's go over to the other side of the lake
那他們怎麼樣?
They got on a boat and they set out
是不是?
他們沒有看天氣報告
那他們出發的時候
那又怎麼樣?
A squall came over the lake
OK
So that the boat was being swamped
他們在哪裡?
現在他們在哪裡?
叫做什麼?
什麼湖?
叫做什麼湖?
Let's look at the next slide
他們現在在哪裡?
Lake of Galilee
Sea of Galilee
是不是?
在上面那裡的
Do you remember?
OK
It's in Galilee
那Sea of Galilee是怎麼樣的?
我們看個地圖
那個湖是低的
OK
The lake is low
And usually
那個天氣
那個溫度會怎麼樣?
那個湖的溫度會怎麼樣?
是會熱一點的
OK
It's a bit warmer
但是這裡上面
是有什麼?
這裡上面有什麼?
我們看個圖
有山的
OK
那山的天氣是怎麼樣的?
平時
山的天氣是怎麼樣的?
是冷的
The temperature is cold
那
The mountain temperature
和那個sea的temperature是熱的
Mixed together
那時候
那會怎麼樣?
What happens?
There will be storms
OK
And that is why
是頗為常見的
會有storm
in the Sea of Galilee
So we look
at the first two S's
We take steps to follow Jesus
And then we encounter a storm
We encounter a storm
有時我們是不是跟隨耶穌的時候呢?
我們都會
hit the storms of life
有時神叫我們去這裡
或者那裡
去這間學校
但是我們都會有face storms
或者我們去大學
都會face storms
我們有不同的career choice
我們真的跟隨神的
但是我們都會face the storms of life
好像2019的時候
Next slide
我們是去了台灣mission trip的
台灣mission trip
我們去台灣mission trip是九個人的
OK
那你知道有時去mission trip
有些人是很空閒的
誰是很空閒的?
是不是Maurice?
是不是Maurice很空閒?
Not you, Uncle Vincent
你好像剛剛進來而已
有些人經常遲到的
OK
我們有九個人
三個人是很enthusiastic的
是我和兩個
一個student
有一個auntie
是很enthusiastic的
Let's go
去傳福音
有三個是很normal的
OK
Who thinks that they are the normal people?
就是會投入
跟隊
是不是?
Whatever the group is doing
We go and serve together
OK
但是有三個是很difficult的
They were the storms in our mission trip
哈哈哈哈
有一個是不睡覺的
應該是睡覺的時候
他不知道要做功課
然後又要做一些coding
他可能三四點才睡覺
然後他第二天又不起來
是要幾個女生去叫他起來才起來
有一個女生是很有態度的
Why do we have to do this?
為什麼要做這個?
I don't do this kind of thing
好像有些你認識的朋友是這樣的
很有態度的
OK
還有一個
其實是我的同事
哈哈哈哈
他經常又肚子痛
又頭痛
又心痛
哈哈哈哈
什麼都痛的
OK
在這個旅程
什麼storm都是upon her life
OK
所以要send
有人有什麼心痛、頭痛
要send有一個人要幫他
是不是?
所以我們就
我做的leader就是
哎呀神啊你差遠我們去台灣這個mission trip
我們很想去教英文去幫這些學生
但是為什麼有這麼多storms of life
哈哈哈哈
這麼多storms of life
所以
You never know
OK
你去mission trip
Who are the storms of the life?
哈哈哈哈
所以這個是一個promotion
for our Taiwan mission trip
我們這個summer是會有Taiwan mission trip
If you are the storm of our life
We will pray to the lord over the storm
哈哈哈哈
To calm the sea
OK
好我們現在有discussion time
第一個問題是
Have we taken steps to follow the lord and hit a storm?
我們是不是跟隨神
但是我們跟隨神的時候
都是有storm的
Have we hit a storm in our life?
然後你怎麼回應?
第二個問題
When you cried out to the lord in panic
可能你有個storm的時候
可能你肥了個test
可能你入了個大學
很難
可能你入了這個company
哇那些人很難相處
What did you do?
How did you cry out to the lord?
然後是不是有一個時間
You felt like god did not answer
好像耶穌在睡覺的時候
沒有answer來的
OK let's go into our groups
Mentors go find students
We will talk and have four minutes of discussion
OK
有沒有人想分享她的storm
誰想分享她的storm
Who wants to share
Ladies who wants to share their storm
Um like if I didn't practice enough for an instrument
好還有誰想share their storm
Who wants to share their storm
我覺得就是要做一個好的基督徒
就是因為你這個世界有很多temptations那些東西
然後如果你要做到像聖經那樣說
是很難的
So we are in our storm right now
And so we can't really share about it
Yeah
OK, in the middle of the storm
Yeah, in the middle of the storm
OK
我剛才share了一個就是
Like because I'm doing part-time ministry
And like a lot of people actually like judge
Like what you're doing
And would actually call you names
Even including like cuss words to describe
Like you guys as like us as Christians
And I'm like
So sometimes in that sense
You should feel like quite offended right
But I feel like because I know what I'm doing
And because I have like god being there
So I'm actually at peace
And I wouldn't be really offended by these things
And actually I would spend time
To understand why they would have such assumptions
OK, good sharing
OK, let's give a hand to everybody who shared
OK, 對了
我們有時跟隨耶穌的時候
We will face the storms of life
之前我可能share過
Next slide
有一日我是
我是在kayaking
OK, 誰去過香港kayaking
Who's been kayaking before
OK, 有兩隻kayak
有一個是sit on的kayak
有一個是sit in的
sit in那些是有個洞的
然後你坐進去
應該你穿了一個叫什麼
Skirt, right
Skirt, prevent water to go in
OK, 那有一天
我跟我的朋友就去了西貢那裡
我們租了一個sit in的kayak
因為我們覺得快一點
這個sit in的, OK
然後我們
It's a sunny day
It's a beautiful day
然後開始下雨了
下雨之後
那些雨會全部下到哪裡
那個sit in的boat那裡
是不是
那我們沒有一個skirt
To prevent water to come in, right
So that's the problem
That's the problem
然後那些浪又那麼大
轉了
我們之後found out
It turned into T1
Ha ha ha ha
Turned into T1
那我們
我們餐廳那時候
Not the slide yet
我的朋友就從筆水出去
And then what happened
We sank
Sank
你知不知道那個kayak有多重
Fill 完水的時候
How heavy is it
It's super heavy
It's like six gallons of water
OK
那些浪又大
那我們一去到一個island那裡
就有人call我們
Ha ha ha ha
不是,我們call on the lord
然後
There's two people there
For some reason
有兩個外國人
They're like
Oh, we were just about to go fishing here
Ha ha ha ha
I don't know why
他們就幫我們lift the boat out of the water
And then we emptied the kayak
And then we tried to go back to the main area
那我們kayak去the main area那裡
然後又很大雨
然後又drown了
We drowned a second time
我們那裡有些yacht
那些yacht的人過來幫我們倒水出去
那個kayak
And then we swam back
And then we kayaked back to shore
So that was the storm of life
其實
The first time we flipped the boat
The boat sank 那個時候
Kayak sank 那個時候
I prayed the prayer
I'm like, God, you can calm the storm
Can you calm the storm now
但是神沒有聽我的
我可能不夠信心
I did not have enough faith
那天
耶穌那天
What happened?
The storm hit
是很大雨
The boat was about to sink
那耶穌是怎樣?
耶穌是在睡覺
Let's see the next slide
為什麼耶穌在睡覺?
這個這麼大的storm
Why is there still Jesus sleeping?
為什麼耶穌在睡覺?
有沒有人知道
是不是好像被嬰兒吵醒的時候
睡得很熟?
是不是?
好像坐巴士
有些人喜歡坐巴士睡覺
有一天有個service
有些tour bus
你可以take a nap
是不是?
No, it's because why?
Because God, Jesus
is not affected by the storm
為什麼?
Because He
It shows that He has true trust in the Father
The storm does not affect Him
He is in control of the storm
明白嗎?
There is stillness
Because Jesus is secure
in the presence of the Father
He is in control
God is in control
And Jesus is in submission to that
好,第一我們是看the storm
第二是什麼?
The scream
我們有沒有一個situation
是panic的
So let's go to the next slide
Hi, next slide
Yes, panic
他們panic
The disciples went and woke him
saying, "Master, Master, we are going to drown"
耶穌啊
我們快要
drown了
是不是?
We are about to drown
Was there a time in your life
where you panicked?
You're like, "Jesus, we're about to drown"
Was there a time in your life
that you were
you felt like you were going to panic and drown?
有沒有?
Next slide
有幾個summer之前
We were in Tunisia
This is where they filmed Lord of the Rings
Not Lord of the Rings
Star Wars
有沒有人看過Star Wars?
Star Wars? Yes
So we were in Tunisia
我們去這個錄影地點的時候
是要去沙漠的
有些騙子
你知道這些騙子
他就說
你給我50歐元
我們就會帶你去這個錄影地點
OK
有些人就說
不用
你自己開車去就可以了
你開車去沙漠就可以了
Just go through
follow Google Maps
跟著路線就可以了
我們就覺得
不用跟這些騙子
不給他們
不想給他們錢
我們就自己去
自己去
我們去到了
我們有這個很棒的錄影地點
很棒的錄影地點
但我們回去的時候
就擋塞了
你可以想像
在Tunisia夏天的天氣是怎樣的
大概是40度
你有沒有去過沙漠
是40度的
有沒有水的?
沙漠是沒有水的
40度
我們駕駛來駕駛去
都好像沒有出口一樣
我們看Google Maps
為什麼轉來轉去
都好像是那個地方
然後我們就看到一些路線
是超過一個沙漠
你知道沙漠是什麼嗎?
沙漠是像一座山
像那裡那些沙漠一樣
我們看到有些路線是超過沙漠的
那我們就嘗試
我們不知道
我們試試看
可能是超過沙漠
我們一去到超過沙漠
然後怎樣?
我們就陷入沙漠
那我就開始慌了
我就開始慌了
我們在40度
太陽超級熱
我們有限量的水
我們就陷入沙漠
在那一瞬間
有一個人在摩托車上
有一個本地人在摩托車上
我們叫他過來
他就叫我們推著摩托車
他進了摩托車
他叫我們推著摩托車
1、2、3 推著
然後摩托車就反轉了
我們就回到山頂
然後我們就給他錢
他就帶我們通過沙漠
我們就開始慌了
在那一瞬間
不知為何有一個本地人
我到達了
然後他幫助我們
所以那裡有恐慌
那裡有恐慌
那些門徒在沉澱的時候
那艘船快要塌下來
他們是很恐慌的
但是怎樣?
神顯示了祂的力量
耶穌起身
下一頁
耶穌起身的時候
他就平靜了沙漠
Be still
好像我們剛才唱的那首歌
是不是?
Be still
剛才那首歌叫做"Still"
當他說"Be still"
好像什麼?
好像耶穌趕鬼的時候
同樣的力量
同樣的
"Get away from this man"
"Satan, get away from this man"
他的指令讓Satan離開
是同樣的
跟沙漠一樣
Be still
明白嗎?
是耶穌的力量
那裡有恐慌
還有力量
OK
第一個"S"是沙漠
第二個"S"是什麼?
The scream
是不是?
耶穌在沙漠裡大叫
And it was silent
Commanded the storm to be silent
第三個是"Scrutiny"
Scrutiny is questioning
Scrutiny is under investigation
第一個"P"是Probe
Where is your faith?
耶穌跟門徒說
你的信心在哪裡?
Where is your faith?
He asked his disciples
為什麼他要跟門徒這樣說?
之前這個章節
那些門徒看到什麼?
The healing
The feeding of the five thousand
耶穌是治了很多人
治了
我們之前已經看過
是不是?
有四個朋友
大個朋友
落在屋頂
And he was healed
不單止他Physically healed
His sins were forgiven
是不是?
我們看到
那些門徒是看到
The feeding of the five thousand
The four thousand
他們看到很多不同的Miracle
所以主耶穌就跟他們說
Where is your faith?
那些門徒看到
耶穌Calming the storm
他們就很Profound
Who is this?
He even commands the winds
and the waters to obey Him
He is the Lord over the storm
He is the Lord over nature
He is the most powerful God
And the one and only God
True God
我們看到The storm
The scream
The scrutiny
第四我們是看The solution
Number four, the solution
有幾個Application
第一
We will face the storm
昨天發生什麼事?
What happened yesterday?
打仗
A new war
US and Israel attacked Iran
And then Iran fired back different missiles
And they attacked not only US
They attacked Dubai
Bahrain
Kuwait
全部都被攻擊
Pastor John is in Dubai
For a conference
And I was like
Wow, are you okay?
Are you okay?
我們跟隨耶穌的時候
Sometimes God will lead us to a conference
I don't know why He went to a conference
When He knew that there were
One third of the US army was surrounding Iran
Sometimes we lead ourselves to the storm
Which might not be good
Sometimes we will face the storm
可能我們是在考DSE
可能我們自己犯罪
令到我們去面對這個風暴
Sometimes we will follow God
And it goes into a storm
好像我剛才說的台灣Story
We will face the storm
In the midst of the storm
你可能是Mental depression
可能是Physical injury
可能是Stress from school
Or parents or different things
What will you fear?
你是怕什麼?
Do you fear the storm?
Or do you fear God?
The second solution is
We need to fear God over the storm
God is greater than the storm
耶穌是bigger than the storm
He is the God over the storm
Jesus was sleeping
Because he had peace
Knowing God was in control
God the Father ultimately is in control
And in authority
Jesus was sleeping
Because he had peace
True peace
我們面對生命的風暴時
我們怕誰?
我們怕那個風暴?
還是我們怕神?
That God is truly in control of our life
That He is sovereign
He has authority and power
Face the storm
Fear God over the storm
第三是
Faith in the captain over the commissar
這是什麼意思?
What does it mean?
It means that we have faith in Jesus as our captain
More than we have faith
in whatever the situation is
很多時我們
We have faith that
有沒有你的朋友經常說
I believe things will work out
有沒有人和你這樣說?
I believe everything will be okay
這個是不是神的說法
應該是Hollywood這樣說
Everything will be okay
There is a hero
The hero is in you
這些pop song是這樣說的
Everything will work out
這個是blind faith
This is not what the Bible says
The Bible says
我們這個世界是有罪的
這個世界是corrupted的
We will face the storms of life
You will have problems
We will one day have physical problems
我們可能有一天會有depression
We go through different things in life
Because God has warned us
This world is not perfect
這個世界不是完美的
Where will it be perfect?
One day in the new heaven and the new earth
Not in this earth
This world has been corrupted
It has sin
It has problem
Sin has results
The result of sin is punishment
Ultimately
我們每人都會有punishment
For our sin
We do something wrong
There is punishment
But we need to have faith in the captain
Over the calm sea
這個世界有時會有calm sea
但有時都會有rough waters
有時會有storm
In the midst of the calm sea
the rough waters or the storm
Our faith is in who?
In Jesus as our captain
如果我們有信心
耶穌是我們的captain
It doesn't matter what the situation is
明白嗎
That's what it means
Faith in the captain over the calm seas
It doesn't matter what the situation is
If who is your captain
Jesus is your captain
It doesn't matter
How many DSE exams you go through
If Jesus is your captain
It doesn't matter
How much money is in your bank account
If Jesus is your captain
It doesn't matter how many friends
Betray you or are with you
As long as Jesus is your captain
你明不明白
耶穌是你的captain
是最重要
你相信他
去帶領你
Through rough waters, calm storms
Not calm storms
Calm seas or the storm
It doesn't matter
You believe in the captain
你明不明白
It doesn't matter which university I go to
Or what job I'll have
As long as Jesus is my captain
I will be okay
Because I believe
He gives me true peace
Do you understand
And the last thing is
We need to have forgiveness
Over our little faith
Forgiveness over our little faith
門徒見了這麼多miracle
門徒見了
The sick being healed
Leprosy being healed
The 5000 being fed
但是他們都沒有
沒有什麼
沒有faith
They lost faith
In the moment of panic
We need to ask for forgiveness
Because we have little faith
In our captain
Jesus is our captain
He is the Lord over nature
And he is the Lord over the storm
He is the Lord over the storm
我們閉上眼睛
As the worship team comes up
Let's close our eyes
Who is the captain of your life
Are you leading the boat yourself
If you are leading the boat yourself
You are counting on yourself
To go through the storms of life
You are relying on yourself
To go through DSC
To go through
To overcome your addictions
Of your cell phone
Of lust
Of relationships
You are relying on yourself as captain
Or do you want to surrender
Do you want to surrender
To the Lord
Surrender to the Lord as your captain
Who is your captain
Who is the true captain of your life today
Is it Jesus Christ
The Lord over nature
The Lord of true blessing
The Lord over the storm
Or are you choosing to trust yourself
As captain in your life
Let's take a moment
To ask for forgiveness for ourselves
That we lack faith in the captain
And surrender ourselves to the Lord
Let's take one minute
To ask for forgiveness for the lack of faith
Father forgive us
For the little faith that we have
We've seen your miracles
We've seen miracles in our friends' lives
In those in church
Student stories
But in the moment of panic
We have lacked faith in you as our captain
Forgive us Lord
I want us now to surrender ourselves
To Jesus as the captain of our life
Does anybody want Jesus
To be the captain of their boat
Of their life
Raise your hand
That they want Jesus to lead their life
Through their storms of life
Through the rough waters
Does anybody want Jesus
To be the captain of their life
They don't want to trust
Ourselves anymore
For our school
For our work
For our friends
For our family
We want to trust Jesus
As the captain of our boat
Of my life
Cause when he is the captain
It doesn't matter
How rough the waters are
All that matters
Is to know that he is in control
If you want Jesus to be captain of your life
Say this prayer with me
Jesus, I ask for forgiveness
Let's pray together
One, two, three
Jesus, I ask for forgiveness
That I have trusted myself as captain
That I have depended on my own works
That I have relied on myself
Forgive me
I now surrender my life
To Jesus as captain of my boat
The boat of my life
I trust that you are Lord over the storm
Whatever I face in my life
I will be with you
You are my shepherd
You are my captain
Help me, Lord
In Jesus' name I pray
Amen
Let us stand and respond in song